<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title> - Christianity</title>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://eliasprescott.github.io/tags/christianity/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://eliasprescott.github.io"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2025-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://eliasprescott.github.io/tags/christianity/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Study of Ephesians Chapter 2</title>
        <published>2025-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Elias Prescott
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://eliasprescott.github.io/blog/ephesians-2/"/>
        <id>https://eliasprescott.github.io/blog/ephesians-2/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://eliasprescott.github.io/blog/ephesians-2/">&lt;p&gt;To set the stage, as I go through some of Paul&#x27;s more minor books in the New Testament, I am trying to focus on how Paul affected the shape of the modern church, but also how he affected modern society.
I am influenced in this idea by books such as &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thegoodbook.com&#x2F;the-air-we-breathe&quot;&gt;The Air We Breathe&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by Glen Scrivener and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.amazon.com&#x2F;Dominion-Christian-Revolution-Remade-World&#x2F;dp&#x2F;0465093507&quot;&gt;Dominion&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by Tom Holland (the historian, not the actor who played Spider-Man).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The common thread I find in both these books is the idea that the foundation of modern society and modern morality is Christianity.
The world that the Ancient Romans and Greek lived in was radically different than the world we live in today.
Their assumptions about freedom, justice, and morality were completely different from the ideals that we hold today in Western society.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;body&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h5 class=&quot;label&quot;&gt;Ephesians 2:1-3 (CSB)&lt;&#x2F;h5&gt;

    &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; And you were dead in your trespasses and sins
&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; in which you previously walked according to the ways of this world, according to the ruler of the power of the air, the spirit now working in the disobedient.
&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; We too all previously lived among them in our fleshly desires, carrying out the inclinations of our flesh and thoughts, and we were by nature children under wrath as the others were also.
  &lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, I think the imagery of being &quot;dead&quot; in our trespasses and sins is an important reminder.
From our own lives and from all of human history, we have seen how we humans tend to mess things up when left to our own devices.
We crave meaning in our lives and we desire justice and fulfillment, but we struggle to find that.
Instead of finding the meaning we seek, we often struggle in vain or lose our way and believe that there is no meaning or purpose to life.
When we live our lives in this way, it is almost as if we are dead.
We are going through the motions of life without clear direction, relying on our base instincts and desires to guide us.
I think this is what Paul means when he says we walk &quot;according to the ways of this world.&quot;
We live in confusion and chaos because we so easily become blinded to the true meaning of life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;body&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h5 class=&quot;label&quot;&gt;Ephesians 2:4-5 (CSB)&lt;&#x2F;h5&gt;

    &lt;sup&gt;4&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; But God, who is rich in mercy, because of his great love that he had for us,
&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; made us alive with Christ even though we were dead in trespasses. You are saved by grace!
  &lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though we are dead in our ways of living, God has taken mercy upon us by sending Jesus to save us.
We take this for granted sometimes as Christians, but this point of view requires an incredible amount of humility.
To willingly partake of the grace that God is extending to us, we have to truly believe that we are in desperate need of such grace.
We have to believe that we are sinful, that we have made a mess of things on Earth.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the phrase &quot;made us alive with Christ.&quot;
Jesus&#x27; live, death, and resurrection quite literally saved us from death.
His death was a means of granting us life.
It was a way of reminding us of the life we are truly meant to live, and it provides us a path towards finding that life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;body&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h5 class=&quot;label&quot;&gt;Ephesians 2:8-10 (CSB)&lt;&#x2F;h5&gt;

    &lt;sup&gt;8&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; For you are saved by grace through faith, and this is not from yourselves; it is God’s gift,
&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; not from works, so that no one can boast.
&lt;sup&gt;10&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; For we are his workmanship, created in Christ Jesus for good works, which God prepared ahead of time for us to do.
  &lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verse 8 is a great verse that you may recognize.
The debate over works versus grace is a common one in Christian circles.
Every Christian group believes that God&#x27;s grace is vital to the process of our salvation, but many groups argue over the role that our faith plays in the process.
Many people have gotten down in the weeds to argue about this topic, but I think everything you need to understand about it is presented clearly in these verses.
We are saved by God&#x27;s grace through our faith.
I believe our faith is a factor because God wants it to be.
God desires a close relationship with us and he wants to save us, but he will not force a relationship with us if we are not willing.
Faith is our way of accepting God&#x27;s mercy and entering into a relationship with him.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it&#x27;s interesting how verse 10 says we are &quot;created in Christ Jesus for good works.&quot;
Even though our works do not save us, clearly works still play a role in the equation.
I&#x27;ve often heard that works are a product of faith, which I think is a good way of looking at it.
Again, it&#x27;s important to emphasize that we are not earning our salvation at all.
Even whenever Paul mentions the good works that we are created for, he specifies that God &quot;prepared [the works] ahead of time for us to do.&quot;
There is nothing that we can give to God that he does not already have.
Literally anything that I have, anything that I am capable of providing, I only have it because God created it and me.
So I cannot bring anything to the table that God would need.
My faith or my belief in God is simply my way of coming to the table.
God does not need or want me to bring anything to the table, he just wants me to sit with him and enter into that relationship with him.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;body&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h5 class=&quot;label&quot;&gt;Ephesians 2:11-22 (CSB)&lt;&#x2F;h5&gt;

    &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; So, then, remember that at one time you were Gentiles in the flesh, called “the uncircumcised” by those called “the circumcised,” which is done in the flesh by human hands.
&lt;sup&gt;12&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; At that time you were without Christ, excluded from the citizenship of Israel, and foreigners to the covenants of promise, without hope and without God in the world.
&lt;sup&gt;13&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; But now in Christ Jesus, you who were far away have been brought near by the blood of Christ.
&lt;sup&gt;14&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; For he is our peace, who made both groups one and tore down the dividing wall of hostility. In his flesh,
&lt;sup&gt;15&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; he made of no effect the law consisting of commands and expressed in regulations, so that he might create in himself one new man from the two, resulting in peace.
&lt;sup&gt;16&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; He did this so that he might reconcile both to God in one body through the cross by which he put the hostility to death.
&lt;sup&gt;17&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; He came and proclaimed the good news of peace to you who were far away and peace to those who were near.
&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; For through him we both have access in one Spirit to the Father.
&lt;sup&gt;19&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; So, then, you are no longer foreigners and strangers, but fellow citizens with the saints, and members of God’s household,
&lt;sup&gt;20&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; built on the foundation of the apostles and prophets, with Christ Jesus himself as the cornerstone.
&lt;sup&gt;21&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; In him the whole building, being put together, grows into a holy temple in the Lord.
&lt;sup&gt;22&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; In him you are also being built together for God’s dwelling in the Spirit.
  &lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&#x27;t want to split up this group of verses because they flow so well together.
Sometimes you just have to let Paul preach and stay out of his way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section is a perfect example of Paul working to bring together Jew and Gentile and unite them under one God.
He starts by acknowledging the separation.
He acknowledges that the Ephesians were Gentiles in the flesh, separate from Israel.
He is honest and said that without God, the Gentiles were without hope.
But in Jesus, all who were far away have been brought near.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going back to what I mentioned at the beginning about the effects of Paul&#x27;s writings on modern morality and society, what I find interesting here is the idea of cross-cultural community.
There was some homogenization between cultures at the time (e.g. Diaspora Jews), but not in the same way that there is today.
For much of their history, many Jews were very untrusting and even hateful towards Gentiles.
And the Greeks and Romans had their fair share of spite towards the Jews.
When Paul talks about Jesus uniting Jews and Gentiles, he is talking about a kingdom that crosses cultures in a revolutionary way.
This is something we take for granted in the United States because we are known as a cultural melting pot.
This idea of mixing cultures and tolerating other people&#x27;s culture is celebrated today, but it certainly would not have been in Paul&#x27;s day.
This is one way in which we can see the effects of Paul&#x27;s writing and Christianity in general on our modern society.
I think you could pick nearly any point in human history, and you will find devout Christians who are crossing societal barriers because their devotion to God is greater than their devotion to culture.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find it very interesting how Paul brings up the law in verse 15.
I can understand why a lot of Jews of the time did not believe in Jesus and were not willing to follow Christianity.
Saying that Jesus made the law &quot;of no effect&quot; would have been a scandalous idea to many Jews in that time.
I believe when Paul talks about Jesus creating one new man from the two, and doing this to reconcile both groups to God in one body, he is saying that Jesus&#x27; life and crucifixion are more important than the law.
A better way of saying it might be that Jesus was the ultimate fulfillment of the law.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an interview recently, biblical scholar and apologist Wes Huff talked about how the law was essentially a mirror to the Jews.
It was a mirror because they were supposed to use it to reveal when they were dirty.
But instead of using the law as a mirror to reveal something about themselves, Wes said the Jews often tried to use the law to clean themselves.
The idea of cleaning yourself with a mirror is preposterous, but I like the metaphor because it shows how the Jews had perverted the law which they had been given.
They were trying to use the law in ways that it wasn&#x27;t meant to be used, oftentimes making it into a stumbling block that took them even further than God.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Jewish law is a mirror that shows people they are dirty, then Jesus is the water that cleanses us.
Jesus is the fulfillment of all the prophecies and promises in the Old Testament.
Jesus is God&#x27;s ultimate method for sanctifying humanity and reconciling us to him.
To those Jews who blindly followed their laws without ever understanding the character of God, Jesus was a blasphemer.
To those Gentiles who ignored or doubted Jesus, he was just another failed Jewish Messiah, condemned to a criminal&#x27;s death.
But to the Jews and Gentiles who listened to Jesus and believed, he is salvation.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe we have the same choice today.
We live in a world that is suffering from pain and confusion.
People are broken, desperately searching for meaning and fulfillment.
If we listen to Jesus and accept him as our king, then we will no longer be &quot;foreigners and strangers&quot;, but we will instead be &quot;fellow citizens with the saints, members of God&#x27;s household.&quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Study of Philippians 2:12-30</title>
        <published>2025-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Elias Prescott
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://eliasprescott.github.io/blog/phillipians-2-part-2/"/>
        <id>https://eliasprescott.github.io/blog/phillipians-2-part-2/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://eliasprescott.github.io/blog/phillipians-2-part-2/">&lt;aside class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;body&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h5 class=&quot;label&quot;&gt;Note&lt;&#x2F;h5&gt;

    I have recently switched to using the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;csbible.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Christian Standard Bible (CSB)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for most of my private study and verse references.
I have found it to be just as accurate as mainstream translations like the ESV, while also flowing more naturally by using a more modern, colloquial English.
If you haven&#x27;t before, I would recommend you try reading it side-by-side with your primary translation and see what you think.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An interesting comparison to the ESV in this study comes from the end of Philippians 2:16.
The CSB renders &quot;Then I can boast in the day of Christ that I didn’t run or labor for nothing&quot;, while the ESV reads &quot;so that in the day of Christ I may be proud that I did not run in vain or labor in vain.&quot;
The CSB feels much more compact and uses the contraction &quot;didn&#x27;t&quot;, which is part of why I think it feels so natural to read.
  &lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start off, we can refresh our memories of where we are in Philippians.
Paul is writing this book from prison, likely in Rome, Caesarea, or possibly &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;hermeneutics.stackexchange.com&#x2F;a&#x2F;77731&quot;&gt;in Ephesus&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
Despite his imprisonment, Paul has spent much of Philippians writing about joy.
He is modeling the attitude that we should have as Christians.
No matter what hardships this life may bring, nothing can take away that joy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, we&#x27;ll be looking at chapter 2, verses 12 through 30.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;body&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h5 class=&quot;label&quot;&gt;Philippians 2:12 CSB&lt;&#x2F;h5&gt;

    Therefore, my dear friends, just as you have always obeyed, so now, not only in my presence but even more in my absence, work out your own salvation with fear and trembling.
  &lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as the believers in Philippi obeyed and believed with Paul, he&#x27;s encouraging them to stay steadfast in his absence.
Paul talking about his absence is a common theme throughout Philippians that we&#x27;ll see more of later.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Work out your own salvation with fear and trembling&quot; is an interesting phrase that you&#x27;ll hear a lot.
At first, it can sound antithetical to the joy that Paul talks about throughout Philippians.
How can Christians be filled with joy, while also having to work out their salvation with fear and trembling?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple answer would be that it&#x27;s just a turn of phrase Paul uses to emphasize the importance of our faith.
Just as the believers obeyed God in the past when God was with them, Paul is emphasizing how they need to continue believing to &quot;work out their salvation.&quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This idea of working out your own salvation can be challenging because it seems opposed to our idea of where our salvation comes from.
We know that our salvation is a gift from God, freely given and never earned.
But how can our salvation be given from God, but also be something we work out?
Working out our salvation sounds awfully close to earning it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We get a good answer to this if we keep reading into verse 13:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;body&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h5 class=&quot;label&quot;&gt;Philippians 2:13 CSB&lt;&#x2F;h5&gt;

    For it is God who is working in you both to will and to work according to his good purpose.
  &lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it&#x27;s God who is working in us.
All we can do is to accept God and his work in us, which results in our salvation.
Working out our salvation is the process of accepting God&#x27;s guidance and will for our lives.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;body&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h5 class=&quot;label&quot;&gt;Philippians 2:14-16 CSB&lt;&#x2F;h5&gt;

    &lt;sup&gt;14&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; Do everything without grumbling and arguing,
&lt;sup&gt;15&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; so that you may be blameless and pure, children of God who are faultless in a crooked and perverted generation,
among whom you shine like stars in the world,
&lt;sup&gt;16&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; by holding firm to the word of life.
Then I can boast in the day of Christ that I didn&#x27;t run or labor for nothing.
  &lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be fine if verse 14 just said &quot;don&#x27;t grumble or argue.&quot;
But instead it says we have to &quot;do everything&quot; without grumbling.
I don&#x27;t know about you, but I find that to be very challenging.
Whenever things in life get hard, or someone does something I don&#x27;t like, a lot of times my first reaction is to complain.
Some of us are worse about complaining than others, but it feels like something we all struggle with at times.
But going back to Paul&#x27;s theme of joy, I think there is little to no room for grumbling if we have a truly joyful heart.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason Paul gives for not grumbling and arguing is very interesting.
&quot;So that you may be blameless and pure, children of God who are faultless in a crooked and perverted generation...&quot;
I think you can find this kind of idea all throughout the Old and New Testaments.
Whether it was the Israelites in the Old Testament, or the early church in the New Testament, God wants his people to stand out from the rest of the world.
As Christians, we are called to a strict standard of living, and it is important that our lives reflect that standard.
If we are constantly grumbling or arguing, then we are not reflecting God to the rest of the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also find the last line interesting: &quot;Then I can boast in the day of Christ that I didn&#x27;t run or labor for nothing.&quot;
So, if I don&#x27;t grumble and if I hold firm to the word of life, then I can boast in Christ that I didn&#x27;t labor for nothing.
First off, I love the idea of boasting in Christ.
I don&#x27;t often boast in myself because I don&#x27;t feel like I have anything worth boasting in.
I think that the world around us is extremely prideful and everyone is far too quick to boast.
So, I like how Christians have our own way that we can boast that still sets us apart from the rest of the world.
Rather than boasting in my myself, I can boast in my Lord.
If something good happens, even if I worked hard for it, I should give the credit to God and boast in him because it is only by him that I can accomplish anything.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also love the idea that we can boast because we didn&#x27;t run or labor for nothing.
Because I don&#x27;t know about you, but I would be a miserable atheist.
I mean it.
If I were an atheist, what would be the point of my life?
If I believed that there was no God or purpose to life, that we were just random flukes drifting in a cold cosmos, then there would be no meaning to my life.
Without God, good and bad and morality lose all meaning.
Without a God, my life would have no purpose.
All my work would be for nothing.
But, because God is real and because I trust in him, I have the confidence that my life is not lived in vain.
Personally, a lot of my joy as a Christian comes from knowing that God has given meaning and purpose to my life.
I can&#x27;t remember the exact video, but in one of his videos, theologian N.T. Wright twists the words of Descartes&#x27;s famous quote &quot;I think, therefore I am.&quot;
Wright says the Christian version is &quot;I am loved, therefore I am.&quot;
The idea being that God&#x27;s love is what gives us meaning, purpose, and value.
To an atheist, this idea is likely offensive (maybe even ludicrous), to a Christian, this idea is beautiful and profoundly true.
It&#x27;s another reason we can find great joy in our Christian faith.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is another interpretation of that last line about boasting in the day of Christ that I almost didn&#x27;t catch at first.
I think it&#x27;s important to notice that Paul is likely referring to himself with that last line.
Verses 14, 15, and the start of 16 are addressing his readers and telling them what they should do.
Then, the latter half of 16 switches to Paul saying that &lt;em&gt;he&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; can boast in the day of Christ &lt;em&gt;if&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; the readers of Philippians take his advice to heart and practice it.
I don&#x27;t think this detail changes my earlier interpretations of the verses, I just thought it was interesting.
I have a bad habit of taking scripture and only applying it to my life and my circumstances.
While I think this is an important thing to do with the Bible, we also cannot forget the different contexts of each book and we must consider who the authors and original readers were.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;body&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h5 class=&quot;label&quot;&gt;Philippians 2:17-18 CSB&lt;&#x2F;h5&gt;

    &lt;sup&gt;17&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; But even if I am poured out as a drink offering on the sacrificial service of your faith, I am glad and rejoice with all of you. &lt;sup&gt;18&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; In the same way you should also be glad and rejoice with me.
  &lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we can see Paul&#x27;s joy in spite of his circumstances.
Even if Paul is &quot;poured out&quot; as a sacrifice, he can still be glad and rejoice.
Paul has such complete trust and faith in God that he is no longer afraid to die.
We know that earlier in Philippians chapter 1, Paul said that he longs to depart and be with Christ.
He has complete faith that God will take care of him while he is alive, and after he passes on.
This level of confidence in God is an important step in a Christian&#x27;s faith.
I believe it goes hand-in-hand with the joy that Paul is talking about.
If we are still afraid of death or of this world, then we will struggle to find the same level of joy that Paul found.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;body&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h5 class=&quot;label&quot;&gt;Philippians 2:19-30 CSB&lt;&#x2F;h5&gt;

    &lt;sup&gt;19&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; Now I hope in the Lord Jesus to send Timothy to you soon so that I too may be encouraged by news about you. &lt;sup&gt;20&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; For I have no one else like-minded who will genuinely care about your interests; &lt;sup&gt;21&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; all seek their own interests, not those of Jesus Christ. &lt;sup&gt;22&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; But you know his proven character, because he has served with me in the gospel ministry like a son with a father. &lt;sup&gt;23&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; Therefore, I hope to send him as soon as I see how things go with me. &lt;sup&gt;24&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; I am confident in the Lord that I myself will also come soon.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;25&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; But I considered it necessary to send you Epaphroditus #— #my brother, coworker, and fellow soldier, as well as your messenger and minister to my need  #— # &lt;sup&gt;26&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; since he has been longing for all of you and was distressed because you heard that he was sick. &lt;sup&gt;27&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; Indeed, he was so sick that he nearly died. However, God had mercy on him, and not only on him but also on me, so that I would not have sorrow upon sorrow. &lt;sup&gt;28&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; For this reason, I am very eager to send him so that you may rejoice again when you see him and I may be less anxious. &lt;sup&gt;29&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; Therefore, welcome him in the Lord with great joy and hold people like him in honor, &lt;sup&gt;30&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; because he came close to death for the work of Christ, risking his life to make up what was lacking in your ministry to me.
  &lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 19, I like how Paul longs to hear news of the believers in Philippi.
With how important the Bible is and the fact that its authors were divinely inspired, it&#x27;s easy to forget that they were human too.
You can see more of Paul&#x27;s humanity in verse 27 where he says that he would have &quot;sorrow upon sorrow&quot; if something were to happen to Epaphroditus.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 25 and onwards, we learn that the Philippian church sent Epaphroditus as a &quot;messenger and minister&quot; to Paul in his time of need.
That is why Paul considered it good that he could send Epaphroditus back to the church, so that Epaphroditus and the church could be reunited.
This whole section may seem minor, but I love it because it&#x27;s an example of the kind of community we should have as Christians.
Paul shows a genuine care for the church and for Epaphroditus, and he indicates that the church was distressed to hear that Epaphroditus was sick.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with joy, this kind of pure Christian community is one of the fruits of faithfulness to God.
Whenever we look past our own needs and desires, we free ourselves up to care more for our fellow man.
The community that we see in the early church is something we should strive to emulate today.
So many Americans are so-called &quot;shallow Christians&quot;, or Christians in name only and not in their deeds.
They treat church as a meaningless ritual or appointment, and they think little of God or their Christian community during the rest of the week.
Church should be so much more than a building we meet in once or twice a week.
A church is supposed to be a community of believers engaged in fellowship and encouragement.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ll close there, but I&#x27;ll leave you with a few questions:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do you think God has been working in your life recently?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is something that you grumble about, and what could you start doing instead of grumbling?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you ever joyful? When? Or why?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is something you could do to engage more with your fellow Christians?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
